hello everyone this is Frankie Freitas
and welcome to a special broadcast of
holotalk Buenos Dias it is
special production in Hotel so I would
like to take this opportunity to thank
you for inviting me and Mario Andres
into your homes your schools and your
businesses
we're going to do this broadcast so that
you can learn a little bit about lasers
and holography
this is the first
series of broadcasts that will be going
out to many different countries around
the world in their native languages
so let's move on with the show
let's start off by asking the question
what is a hologram
a hologram is a three-dimensional
picture
when you take a picture with a camera it
is
[Music]
when you make a hologram it has three
dimensions
Holograms can appear so real all of them
sometimes you are fooled into thinking
that what you are seeing is right in
front of you this is
a hologram foreign
[Music]
with education
Holograms can show the three-dimensional
structure of an atom in education for
example
if you wear jeans you may find holograms
on your clothes
so that they are not counterfeited or
and in museums you may see Holograms as
fine arts places
where artists use the three-dimensional
properties of holography to express
themselves
now at this point you may be asking is
what do Holograms and lasers have in
common
well the truth is you do not need a
laser to see a hologram but you need a
laser to make one David that is
now there are also many uses for lasers
besides holography
such as medicine where you may have
surgery using a laser company
the engineering lasers may be used to
make very precise measurements
lasers are used for communications
when you make a long-distance phone call
and you speak to your friends and family
far away many times your voice is
carried by a laser beam us
all of these applications require people
to work in the field is
and someday you may find yourself
working with lasers as your job
with holography we use lasers to make
Holograms
a laser provides the special light
needed in order to make the Hologram
last it is
there are different types of lasers used
to make Holograms
there are gas lasers there are glasses
such as helium neon lasers
when electricity is applied to the gas
in the tube it begins to Glow
electricity is
and it is reflected back and forth
between two mirrors that are on the ends
of the tube e s reflects
into those middle
um
in
people and exits through one of the
mirrors as a laser beam is
this laser light is then used to
illuminate whatever you're making a
hologram of
illuminated
and that light is then recorded on a
special photographic plate is
[Laughter]
which is made specially for Holograms
owner like a hspc online
recently we found a new way to make
Holograms
and we do not require the very expensive
gas lasers
we use very inexpensive lasers called
laser diodes
have you ever seen a laser pointerest
well there's a diode laser inside of
that laser pointer which
is
and we have made Holograms using a laser
pointer yes
this has created quite a bit of
excitement in the field of holography
because it opens the field up to very
very many people okay
who would not have had the opportunity
to do holography before
and perhaps soon you will be making
holograms on your own
foreign
in closing I would like to thank you
very much for tuning in to the show
I know we didn't have a lot of time to
cover very many things
but I hope it at least make you a little
more interested in lasers and holography
and on your own you will search out
information on the field
so I would like to thank Mario Andres
Nunez for doing the translations for
this show
and I would like to thank Elena Strobel
for doing the technical production in
the studio
and thank you very very much for tuning
in and it was an honor to be invited
into your homes schools and businesses
good day I think I'm Wendy